Guide to the Stanford Prevention Research Center, Five-City Project, videorecordings SC1310
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Prevention Research Center, Five-City Project, videorecordings
1980-1984
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Farquhar, John W.
Stanford Prevention Research Center
SC1310
7.5 Linear Feet (5 boxes)
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research use; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of John W. Farquhar, 2016.
Biographical / Historical
The Five City Project education campaign began in 1978 and ran for six years. Monterey and Salinas were chosen as education communities; Modesto, San Luis Obispo and Santa Maria were chosen as controls. The campaign was aimed at the entire population, including teenagers. The media campaign was designed to test if measurable risk reduction could be produced in a free-living population.
Scope and Contents
Collection includes videorecordings from the Five City Project education campaign.
Coronary heart disease -- Prevention; Farquhar, John W.; Stanford Prevention Research Center
- Videorecordings, Accession ARCH-2017-096
  - Smoking Show Series, undated; sc1310_1; 1 videotape(s) (Box 1)
  - Smoking News Series, undated; sc1310_2; 1 videotape(s) (Box 1)
  - Calling it Quits. Smoking Show., 1982 Apr; sc1310_3; 1 videotape(s) (Box 1)
  - Animation, Veriation Films, Series 11 & 12, 1980 Mar 19; sc1310_4; 1 videotape(s) (Box 1)
  - Cooking Show, Day 2, undated; sc1310_5; 1 videotape(s) (Box 2)
  - Veriation Films, Stanford University, "Heart Health Test", 1980 Apr 14; sc1310_6; 1 videotape(s) (Box 2)
  - A Change of Heart, 1984 May 31; sc1310_7; 1 videotape(s) (Box 2)
  - Stanford Heart Program, English Copy 1, undated; sc1310_8.1; 1 film reel(s) (35mm) (Box 2)
  - Stanford Heart Program, English Copy 2, undated; sc1310_8.2; 1 film reel(s) (35mm) (Box 2)
  - Stanford Heart Program, Spanish Copy 1, undated; sc1310_8.3; 1 film reel(s) (35mm) (Box 2)
  - Stanford Heart Program, SHDPP NG Second Try, undated; sc1310_8.4; 1 film reel(s) (35mm) (Box 2)
  - Stanford Heart Program, Neg. NG. SHDPP Logo English, undated; sc1310_8.5; 1 film reel(s) (35mm) (Box 2)
  - Stanford Heart Program, First NG Trial, SHDPP Logo, undated; sc1310_8.6; 1 film reel(s) (35mm) (Box 2)
  - Stanford Heart Presentation, Quantel Effects, 1980 Mar 24; sc1310_9; 1 videotape(s) (Box 3)
  - Stanford University Cooking Show, undated; sc1310_10; 1 videotape(s) (Box 3)
  - Smoking Show/Series, SHDPP/KSBW, Bob Drake Interview, undated; sc1310_11; 1 videotape(s) (Box 3)
  - Veriation Films, "Heart Disease", 1980 Mar 13; sc1310_12; 1 videotape(s) (Box 3)
  - Veriation Films, "Heart Disease", 1980 Mar 13; sc1310_13; 1 videotape(s) (Box 4)
  - Veriation Films, "Heart Disease", 1980 Mar 13; sc1310_14; 1 videotape(s) (Box 4)
  - Smoking Class, SHDPP/KSBW, undated; sc1310_15; 1 videotape(s) (Box 4)
  - Stanford University Cooking Show, "Meat/Cheese", undated; sc1310_16; 1 videotape(s) (Box 4)
  - Stanford University Cooking Show, "Protein Cooking Show", 1983 Feb 16; sc1310_17; 1 videotape(s) (Box 5)
  - "Stanford Heart", 1982 Jan 28; sc1310_18; 1 videotape(s) (Box 5)
  - "Stanford Heart Disease/Smoking Class", undated; sc1310_19; 1 videotape(s) (Box 5)
  - "Cooking for Health News Series", undated; sc1310_20; 1 videotape(s) (Box 5)